WhirligigWorld 0.6.0 for KSP 1.3.1, 1.4.5, and 1.5.1.

WhirligigWorld is a mod which moves the Kerbal Space Center to the equator of Mesbin, a rapidly spinning supermassive airless planet. The solar system is also completely rebuilt, turning it into the Kaywell/Gememma binary star system.

Credits:
GregroxMun (Lead developer)
Thomas P., MrHappyFace (Kopernicus Expansion Continued)
NovaSilisko (Feedback, playtesting, the model for the Kaputnik Mk0 Electromechanical Program Executor)
SnailsAttack (Feedback, playtesting)
Niako (Biome map for Lowel)

------------------------------------------------------------------
-----------IMPORTANT KNOWN ISSUE, READ FOR FIX--------------------

The root part of vessels sometimes like to explode. This can be caused by using the teleporter in the cheats menu, and sometimes by s.o.i transitions. No known cure, as it seems to be related simply due to the fact that the space center is so far away from the "sea level."

This can be treated by quicksaving and quickloading to "stabilize" the game any time you're in a safe, stable orbit. Quicksave/quickload as soon as you're in Mesbin space or Mesbin orbit. This gives you a quickload point AND stabilizes the game to make SOI changes less buggy. You should also quicksave before changing SOIs, and quicksave/quickload once you're in the new SOI. The bug also only seems to explode the root part of the vessel. If you make the root part a non-essential part instead of a command pod, you may be able to recover from an explosion.

This is the only bug that comes close to game breaking. That's why I am making such a big deal of it! It is treatable, and I hope that some day there may be a fix for it. Note that this only happens when Mesbin is the homeworld. The bug does not occur when you're playing with the Kerbmun homeworld patch enabled.

------------------------------------------------------------------

LICENSE

Whirligig World: Copyright Gregory Brannon (GregroxMun) 2018. All Rights Reserved.
Kopernicus Expansion Continued: GNU General Public License.

------------------------------------------------------------------

BACKSTORY

Two centuries ago, explorers from the far off planet Kerbin left their home to colonize other star systems. Preliminary transit data suggested the third planet of Kaywell's star had an oxygen atmosphere and water. It did not.

Unable to correct their course due to piloting error, the U.S.C. Manifest Destiny crashed into the massive, 70 Kerbin Mass planet Mesbin. Luckily, Mesbin spins. Once every twenty eight minutes it spins, and the centripetal effect pushes the equator outwards and negates some of the gravity. The 13 gees of gravity at the poles is reduced to a tad over 1.2 gee at the equator.

The payload of the ship survived, but the engines and fuel tanks were reduced to a lot of metal rubble along the surface. Unable to find somewhere else to go, they buried themselves underground and set up a stable ecosystem and environment down there. Eventually the colony was sufficiently industrialized to start looking up again.

------------------------------------------------------------------

MESBIN PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS

MASS = 3.777e24 kg = 71.38 MKerbin
POLAR RADIUS = 1,392,609 m = 2.32 RKerbin
EQUATORIAL RADIUS = 2,367,436 m = 3.95 RKerbin
SPHERICAL DENSITY = 136 g/cm^3 = 2.344 ρKerbin
POLAR GRAVITY = 13.2 G
TRUE EQUATORIAL GRAVITY = 4.58 G
APPARENT EQUATORIAL GRAVITY = 1.286 G
ROTATION PERIOD = 1701 s (28 minutes.)﻿

------------------------------------------------------------------

List of objects: (Descriptions intentionally vague.)

Kaywell: the bright white sun.
-Shol: the hot Jupiter.
-Wolda: an asteroid.
-Tyepolbynar: the temperate Jupiter.
--Jifgif: Found a peanut.
--Imterril: Boiling world.
--Tannor: Shiniboi.
--Etrograd: numarG eb ot desu tI
--Aerious: Rubble or rubbish?
-Wers: Asteroid/dwarf planet coorbital with Mesderbin.
--Vizea: an asteroid orbiting Wers.
-Mesderbin System: Mesbin and Derbin (Sigma Dimensions compatible)
--Mesbin: The homeworld, a heavy pancake planet with no atmosphere.
--Statmun: The static moon.
--Graymun: The grey moon.
--Kerbmun: The blue moon.
--Derbin: The superkerbin hell.
--Derminmus: Is no chocolat
-Valyr: Why didn't we land here instead?
--Denna: red.
--Plaph: potato.
--Oshan: Half ice world, half desert.
--Manonam: Small rocky world.
-Egad: Half desert, half... uh... ice world. In a different way.
--Yeerbor: a large asteroid moon.
-Rik: rock.
-Reander: Gas giant.
--Lito: Fat snowball.
--Yalthe: Fat Io.
--Yokane: A volcanic world.
--Dakkonme: An icy cracked world.
--Totooa: A tectonic icy world.
--Mally: Red snowball.
--Yawer: Mini-Mesbin.
-Fophie: Comet
Gememma: A red dwarf star in the system's outer reaches.
-Ammenon: Hot. (And cool!)
-Lowel: A largely deserted planet.
--Ollym: A desert planet covered in volcanoes.
-Gannovar: Eccentric ice world.
-Mandrake/Rutherford System
--Mandrake: A large ice giant planet.
--Rutherford: A small ice giant planet.
--Lozon: Snowball
--Beagrid: Snowball
--Jancy: Dirty Snowball
--Tatian: Eyeball

------------------------------------------------------------------

Career Mode Notes:

It is refreshing to play in this system if you're already used to career mode.
Do try this in career mode--I've had a lot of fun with this!
The tech tree has been reconfigured to make more sense: 
Aviation node merged with Aerodynamics, and therefore those parts are later in the tree.
The aerodynamics section is subject to change even more...
Field Science Node is now where Aviation was before--rovers before planes!
Science cost and node connections have been rearranged appropriately to fit.
Changed Survivability from basic landing parts to probe cores. It's survivable because it's robots.
Changed Stability icon from a winglet to the flight control icon, along with a few other icon changes.
Landing node now contains the small parachute, the radial drogue chute, and the radial parachute, as well as all heat shields up to 2.5m.
Unlock monopropellant and the linear RCS thruster in Stability.
Both the radial decoupler and the 1.25m decoupler are unlocked in tier 2: Basic Rocketry and Engineering 101 respectively.
Thermometer and Mystery Goo swap places.
Barometer is unlocked earlier--and rebranded as AtMoCo surpluss cavern pressure sensors from a cave-city that lost all its air due to a tragic mistake.
Added a scaled up Stayputnik clone called the Kaptunik, which is very heavy and lacks the internal antenna, BUT it does have full SAS autopilot (Prograde/Retrograde, Radial In/Out, Antinormal/Normal, Full Thrust/Cut Thrust, and Stage.) When you unlock the antenna you of course get all of that and manual control, but it's still really heavy. I may nerf it since I made the normal probe core appear earlier. It will have its own model in the future.
The small ISRU parts are unlocked earlier, so you can take advantage of mining asteroids earlier on.
Pods and Lander Cans have been swapped around.
Making History compatible, partially compatible with other mods.
All bodies have balanced science multipliers and at least basic biome maps.
Science notes:

Only Oshan has biomes (just two very basic ones), everything else has had its biomes removed.
Some planets do have custom science descriptions for some experiments, but not all.
Science has been balanced for career and science modes for all planets, but not fully tested. If you feel you get too much or too little science, let me know.


















